# ASKHAT ASSILBEKOV

#### SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

$\checkmark$	askhat.assilbekov@gmail.com
--------------	-----------------------------

## in Askhat Assilbekov

#### SUMMARY -

I'm a business problem-oriented Senior Front-end Engineer with over 10 years of experience.

My interests include user interfaces for data-related tools, rendering optimization, and developer tooling.

I have a working experience of 3+ years Back-End development experience as a BE team member.

Can lead small/medium-sized teams and/or work highly autonomously and as a part of a team.

#### SKILLS -

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Redux, Golang, gRPC, Python, Swift, MaterialUI, styled-components, GraphQL, Tailwind-CSS, CSS, FastAPI, git, Next.js, fp-ts, Cypress, Jest, NodeJs.

#### EXPERIENCE -

#### 01/2022 - Present Senior Frontend Engineer

Sperta

- Engaged with Sperta, a Silicon Valley startup focused on risk decision platforms. Contributed to the development of a product with complex logic, including diagram makers, a code editor, RBAC, feature flags, and rendering of a vast amount of data.
- · Defined leading technologies, architecture, and code styling patterns so other developers could work independently but as a team.
- · Delivered the working product to clients 4 months before the deadline. With a total of 2 years estimated.
- · Over-performed the company's expectations and covered a need for 2 front-end and 1 back-end developer.
- · Engineered a product adopted by 100+ high-value clients, including a prominent FAANG-level company, contributing to an annual revenue surge exceeding \$1 million.

## 9/2021 - 1/2022 Senior Frontend Engineer

UniCredit

- The second biggest bank in Italy. Annual revenue is \$25.04 B in 2023.
- Finished and successfully released a banking internal tool adopted by 500+ corporate users.
- · Solved the release-blocking issues and delivered a working product a month before the deadline.
- · Quickly on-boarded and started to work on an entirely new coding paradigm as a member of the FP-TS library authors (10k starts on GitHub).

## 5/2020 - 6/2021 Lead Frontend Engineer

Sberbank

- The biggest bank in Russia. Annual revenue is \$31.93 B in 2023.
- Led and mentored a team of 3 engineers to build a tool for issuance of large loans.
- · Dramatically increased the feature delivery time by 80% by improving the code structure and architecture.
- Defined the Front-End development standards, minimizing the amount of bugs by 75%.

#### 10/2017 - 1/2020 Frontend Engineer

LAF24

- · Collaborated as a member of a team of 7 engineers to develop an ERP system with 500+ in-house users.
- · Mentored 1 team member for a comfortable transition from UX designer to Front-end development.
- · Developed in-house design system.

### **EDUCATION**

9/2014 - 7/2018

**Bachelor in Mechatronics and Robotic Systems** 

Tomsk State University

## LANGUAGES -

English - C2, Russian - native, Portuguese - C1, Spanish - C1, French - A2